#### **CURRICULUM VITAE:**

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Name: Kihuga James Muiruri

Gender: Male

Date of birth: 25<sup>th</sup> July 1990

Nationality: Kenyan
County: Nyandarua
Marital status: Single

Language proficiency: English, Kiswahili and Kikuyu

Contact: 0715300844

Home address: P.O Box 629-20303,Olkalou
E-Mail: Smartjmcomps3@gmail.com

Region: Christianity

I am an experienced clerk with exceptional typing and data entry abilities of resultsdriven nature. I am also knowledgeable about customer relations, management, logging daily information, researching variances and maintenance of accurate thorough records.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Kenya Women Finance Trust (K.W.F.T) Bank: Jan 2023.

#### **Business Development Internship**

- > Recruitment of clients and groups for the bank.
- Making follow ups on existing clientele and groups for financing them with credits.
- > Collection of dues from groups and individual from the field.
- Preparation and filing of customers Loans forms.

### Self Employed: From Jan 2016 to date.

# As a seasoned Computer Instructor,

- > Set up computer lab, network systems and delivering a step by step instructions on basic computer applications.
- ➤ Attending professional development courses
- ➤ Development of website using frameworks and use of Html. Css Bootstrap, php and Java scripts inputs.
- > Prepare examination materials and supervision of class projects.

# <u>Independent Electoral & Boundaries Commission: July 2022 – Aug 2022.</u>

# Deputy Returning Officer (DRO)

#### Duties included:-

- Collection and ensuring of safety of IEBC materials.
- Conduct training to the clerks at the polling station.
- Siting organizing and marking of polling centers for elections.
- > Tallying of ballot papers and ensuring conformity to rules and regulations of the commission.

Documentation and coordinating of internal activities at the polling station.

#### D.T. Dobie & Company: Aug 2015 – Dec 2015:

Clerical duties included.

- Provision of quality clerical support through data entry, document management, email correspondence and overseeing of office equipment operations.
- ➤ Interaction with customers through phone, email or in-person in the provision of required information.
- ➤ Production of high-quality communication memos for internal and external use.
- Promotion of customer loyalty, satisfaction and sales.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### EGERTON UNIVERSITY AUG 2010 - DEC 2013

Awarded a Bachelor's Degree in Economics and

**Statistics** 

NJABINI BOYS HIGH SCHOOL: JAN 2005 – NOV 2009

Awarded the Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Qualification (K.C.S.E) Certificate Grade B (Plain).

#### CERTIFICATIONS

MAT ACADEMY: SEP, 2022.

Software Development Course.

Awarded Diploma in Software Development.

# NAMELOK RETREAT CENTER OF GGFAN: 8<sup>TH</sup> JULY 2022

Trauma Healing Facilitators' Course

Awarded, Trauma Healing Facilitator's certificate.

# INTERNATIONAL LEADERSHIP INSTITUTE: 13<sup>TH</sup> - 16<sup>TH</sup> JUNE, 2022

Leadership Training Course.

Awarded Facilitator's Certificate.

#### ST. ANN'S CATHOLIC INSTITUTE: MARCH 2014 - DEC, 2014

Certified Public Accountant (CPA) Course.

Awarded ,C.P.A 2 Certificate.

## **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

- Browsing
- Travelling
- Reading motivational articles
- > Swimming.

### REFEREES

Mr. James Mburu Project Officer Nyandarua Dan Church Aid Project Contact: 0705972771

Pst. Nderitu Stephen, Rev. GGFAN church, P.O Box. 155- 20303, Ol Kalou.

Contact: 0728460062

Fredrick G. Mathenge, P. O. Box 629-20303, OLKALOU.

Contact: 0725630388